<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title type="text">PyCon.DE 2017 &amp; PyData Karlsruhe</title>
  <id>urn:uuid:53af2a09-01da-33dc-9af3-6578c6b0f005</id>
  <updated>2017-09-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <link href="http://de.pycon.org/" />
  <link href="http://de.pycon.org/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <author>
    <name></name>
  </author>
  <generator uri="https://github.com/ajdavis/lektor-atom" version="0.2">Lektor Atom Plugin</generator>
  <entry xml:base="http://de.pycon.org/blog/data-science-meetup/">
    <title type="text">PyCon.DE Data Science Meetup</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:d7c29040-7dca-3cf2-8c9d-8e30cd1e2724</id>
    <updated>2017-09-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://de.pycon.org/blog/data-science-meetup/" />
    <author>
      <name>Peter Hoffmann</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inovex.de/de/&quot;&gt;Inovex&lt;/a&gt; is known for their great &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/de-DE/inovex-karlsruhe/&quot;&gt;meetups&lt;/a&gt; in Karlsruhe. 
We are very happy that they joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://pycon.de&quot;&gt;PyCon.DE&lt;/a&gt; as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://pycon.de/sponsoring/&quot;&gt;Meetup Sponsor&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a data science meetup at the evening of the first conference day (wednesday 25.10.2017) with the following speakers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Florian Schild (boot.ai)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Florian Schild is an Artificial Intelligence expert. He was an officer in the
Air Force, researcher for the Ministry of Defense, worked in established
companies and young start-ups – including Shop.co from Düsseldorf where he
build up the AI-Technology. In his talk, he shows how artificial intelligence
can be applied in companies. He provides valuable impulses, such as the
conceptualization of AI products and strategies, the development of agile AI
teams and the automation of business processes. With his company boot.AI
Florian prepares companies for the new digital age so called artificial
intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Marcel Kurovski (inovex)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“People buying X also bought Y”, “Discover Weekly”, “Top 10 for You” -
personalization of online services by recommendations surrounds everyone in
daily life. To personalize content Amazon, Spotify, Netflix and many more use
Recommender Systems and Machine Learning. This development comes along with
another remarkable trend around learning machines: Deep Learning. Almost daily
we hear about the tremendous progress that makes humans obsolete in more and
more domains: skin cancer detection, No-Limit-Hold'em Heads-Up Poker, or speech
recognition (No, not yet another Alpha-Go example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During his master thesis at inovex Marcel Kurovski studied the application of
Deep Learning for Recommender Systems. He investigated interesting approaches
in this emerging research area. In addition, he developed a system for vehicle
recommendation in TensorFlow based on data from a large German online market
that extends Google’s Wide and Deep Learning approach. In his talk Marcel will
share his insights and those of other big players with you. He will also share
his impressions from the very recent ACM RecSys Conference 2017 in Como which
is the leading conference for recommender systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry xml:base="http://de.pycon.org/blog/pycon-zkm-open-codes/">
    <title type="text">PyCon.DE @ ZKM Open Codes Exhibition</title>
    <id>urn:uuid:0a8229c3-797e-35ed-a93c-76c05352da30</id>
    <updated>2017-09-01T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <link href="http://de.pycon.org/blog/pycon-zkm-open-codes/" />
    <author>
      <name>Peter Hoffmann</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://pycon.de&quot;&gt;PyCon.DE Karlsruhe&lt;/a&gt; becomes a partner of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://zkm.de&quot;&gt;ZKM&lt;/a&gt; - Open Codes exhibition:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hands-on tutorials take place within the exhibition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every PyCon.DE participant gets free access to the museum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will organize guided tours through the Open Codes exhibition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the film presentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://zkm.de/en/event/2017/10/all-watched-over-by-machines-of-loving-grace&quot;&gt;All Watched over by Machines of Loving Grace&lt;/a&gt; within the Open Codes exhibition on thursday 26.10.2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Open Codes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the &lt;a href=&quot;http://zkm.de/en/event/2017/10/open-codes&quot;&gt;Open Codes. Living in Digital Worlds&lt;/a&gt; exhibition (Fri, 20.10.2017 – Sun, 05.08.2018), the ZKM | Karlsruhe is once again addressing the subject of digitalization and the recording of the world through the binary code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the world we inhabit
To understand the world we live in
To understand the world that sustains us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we live in a globalized world that is controlled and created by digital codes. From communication to transportation (of people, goods, and messages), everything is guided by codes that use electromagnetic waves and computers. Mathematics and mechanics have created a new tool-based world, erected by engineers, physicists, and programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the binary code (Leibniz) to Morse code, from cosmic code to the genetic code, we live in a world of codes. This exhibition, a collection of artworks and scientific works gives you the opportunity to get an insight into this world and to better understand it. The exhibition will be a mix of a laboratory and a lounge, a »Club Mediterranée«, and a learning environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to test new and perhaps unusual education and learning formats with our visitors, and create new approaches to knowledge in a relaxed atmosphere that stimulates learning. Programming, learning with bots and other new technologies should no longer pose a limit to education. Everyone should have the chance to understand what lies behind today’s digital world. Whether with free entry to events, snacks and drinks at the museum or natural work in the museum field – the exhibition will change the approach to museum installations as an educational policy experiment in the area of »Audience Development«. The museum will, in the true sense of the word, be well worth a visit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artworks and scientific works based on digital as well as on analog codes are presented in the exhibition. The works visualize and explain the complex dynamics of code, and the way in which they are increasingly shaping the way we live and perceive the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
